Andrei Dan

d2an3m@gmail.com

PROFILE

I am a scientist in Internet of Things Systems & Software at Hitachi ABB Power Grids. Previously, I developed reliable and secure of industrial software solutions and machine learning applications at ABB Corporate Research. During my PhD studies at ETH Zurich, I worked on static code analysis for software correctness and security.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Scientist in Internet of Things Systems & Software Hitachi ABB Power Grids Research, Baden-Dättwil 2020 -

Scientist in Software Security

2018 - 2020

ABB Corporate Research Center, Baden-Dättwil

- IoT project on connecting devices to distributed ledgers for industrial applications
- Improved security and privacy of applications using computation on encrypted data
- Evaluated and improved robustness of machine learning for industrial use cases
- Innovation project on easy robot programming using artificial intelligence

Research Intern 2016

Samsung Research America, Mountain View, USA

- Proved that computing a Context-Free Language minimal cut is NP-hard
- Implemented a fix-location finder for a null-pointer analysis of Java programs

Research Intern 2011 - 2012

IBM Research, Rüschlikon

- Implemented in C a Linux device driver for solid-state hybrid storage systems
- Explored trade-offs between performance and durability of the devices

Research Intern 2010

SRI International, Menlo Park, USA

- Developed using the PVS proof system a verified SAT trace checker
- Increased the confidence in the results of highly-optimized SAT solvers

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Computer Science

2012 - 2018

Software Reliability Lab, ETH Zurich

- Thesis advisor: Prof. Martin Vechev
- Developed new static program analysis for concurrent programs running on multicore processors or high performance networks, part of the Fender project
- Developed part of the Securify analyzer for the security of Ethereum smart contracts

M.Sc Computer Science

2010 - 2012

Ecole Polytechnique Federale de Lausanne

- Fast-track Master program in Computer Science consisting of 90 ECTS credits

Engineer Diploma

2008 - 2010

Ecole Polytechnique Paris, France

- Multidisciplinary scientific education, formal methods for software reliability

B.Sc. Computer Science

2005 - 2009

Polytechnic University of Bucharest, Romania

- Final Project: Designed and implemented a GPS Navigator in Java

Synthesizing False Positive Adversarial Objects Using Generative Models M. Kotuliak, S.E. Schoenborn, A. Dan

Submitted

Fast and Effective Robustness Certification for Recurrent Neural Networks W. Ryou, J. Chen, M. Balunovic, G. Singh, A. Dan, M. Vechev Submitted

Securify: Practical Security Analysis of Smart Contracts P. Tsankov, A. Dan, D. Drachsler-Cohen, A. Gervais, F. Bunzli, M. Vechev CCS 2018

Automatic Verification of RMA Programs via Abstraction Extrapolation C. Baumann, A. Dan, Y. Meshman, T. Hoefler, M. Vechev **VMCAI 2018**

Finding Fix Locations for CFL-Reachability Analyses via Minimum Cuts A. Dan, M. Sridharan, S. Chandra, JB Jeannin, M. Vechev CAV 2017

Modeling and Analysis of Remote Memory Access Programming A. Dan, P. Lam, T. Hoefler, M. Vechev **OOPSLA 2016**

Effective Abstractions for Verification under Relaxed Memory Models A. Dan, Y. Meshman, M. Vechev, E. Yahav VMCAI 2015

Synthesis of Memory Fences via Refinement Propagation Y. Meshman, A. Dan, M. Vechev, E. Yahav **SAS 2014**

Predicate Abstraction for Relaxed Memory Models A. Dan, Y. Meshman, M. Vechev, E. Yahav **SAS 2013**

AWARDS

Distinguished Paper Award at OOPSLA	2016
ACM SIGPLAN Travel Grant for OOPSLA	2016
EPF Lausanne Excellence Scholarship	2010 - 2012
Eiffel Excellence Scholarship (French Ministry of Foreign Affairs)	2008 - 2010

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Program Analysis Graduate Course

Software Architecture and Engineering

2014 - 2018

2013 - 2015

Undergraduate Course

SERVICE

External Review Committee Member

ASPLOS 2020

Program Committee Member

EASE 2019